Gilberto Ramirez | .NET Software Engineer

Summary

I am a skilled software engineer with 4 years of experience in full stack development. I work with .NET, React, and SQL technologies. I have successfully contributed to various projects such as ASP.NET Core Web APIs, data integrations, and UI development.

Skills

C#, .NET Framework/.NET Core, Asp.net Core Web APIs, Entity Framework, Dapper, SQL Server, Microsoft Graph API, Javascript/ES6, React, Git, TFS/Azure DevOps, Material UI, Reactstrap, Formik, YUP, Chrome DevTools, ActiveBatch

Experience

Application Developer | Omnisource Mexico | Jan 2024 - present | Remote

Description: Working with the US team in .Net API developement of an ERP application that manages purchases, transportation, etc.

Full-stack Engineer | DPR Construction | Jan 2021 - jam 2024 | Remote

Description: Participated in the planning, development, and maintenance of ERP applications and data integrations. Some of the ERP applications are: Identity Management, Asset Management, Azure AD Group Management, Company Portal for new Employees.

- Planned, developed, debugged, and maintained REST Web APIs using .NET Core.
- Planned, developed, debugged, and maintained the UI for different web applications using React.
- Planned, developed, maintained, and documented data integrations to third-party applications using NET.
- Mentored and introduced new colleagues to the backend and frontend projects.
- Responsible of the scheduler ActiveBatch. Coordinated the migration of 600+ company jobs to the scheduler. 8 engineers were involved.

Full-stack Developer | GHAPPS | Jan 2019 - Apr 2020 | Colima, Mexico

Description: Participated in the development of a Content Management System for Loro Fan, a mobile app for the University of Colima's soccer team. The app has 100+ downloads.

- Developed and debugged a Content Management System for the mobile app Loro Fan using PHP, Ajax, Javascript/ES6, jQuery, HTML5/CSS, Bootstrap, and AdminLTE.
- Designed and developed the Database for the Content Management System using MYSQL.
- Developed responsive web pages using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and Bootstrap.

Education

Bachelor degree in Software Engineering | University of Colima | 2017-2021 | Colima, Mexico

C# Courses | Plural Sight | 2021 | Online: Beginning Collections, Building an API with ASP.NET Core.

Python for Everybody Specialization | Coursera | 2020 | Online

Bachelor degree in Philosophy | Regina Apostolorum | 2007-2011 | Rome, Italy